

REENA S. BARSAGADE

(Manager-Training and Development)

PROFILE

An enthusiastic learning and development specialist with over 7 years of experience in L&D and teaching along with partial experience in software development, posing knowledge of Process training, experienced in recruiting trainers, verbal and written communication skills. along with delivering impactful trainings that promotes a stimulating learning environment. Currently, exploring motivating opportunities to learn, grow and excel in domain of learning, training and development in corporate sector for contributing to company's and own growth.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-9860927554

WEBSITE:

www.linkedin.com/in/reena barsagade-44287519 (linkedin)

FMAII .

reenabarsagade@gmail.com

HOBBIES

- Exploring online learning content
- 2. Researching LMS
- 3. Creating pedagogical advancement activities
- 4. Watching Ted talks

EDUCATION

- Masters in Computer Application, Raisoni college of Engg. Nagpur
- Diploma in Soft skills and Personality Development, Ramtek University
- BSc Computer science, Hislop College, Nagpur, Maharashtra
- International Certificate "Faculty Development Program" from Wadhwani Global University
- Certificate in "TTT-Train the trainer program" from GE & Tata Strive

WORK EXPERIENCE

Virohan Pvt. Ltd. As a Manager- Training and Development Feb 2018 to Current

- Hiring, Creating and executing impactful Trainings, performance monitoring, initiating RnR
- Hiring and creating facilitators on requisitions of organizations with multiple suitable skills by coordinating with candidates, arranging Interview, following internal benchmarking - offer negotiation to joining of candidate along with ensuring adherence to the recruitment process set by the organization.
- Developing effective impactful training content and updating the content as per organization's need by using variety of tools like media, technology, online tools, offline activities.
- Delivering the planned training sessions effectively as a part of training and development services to self/partner firms along with conduction of assessment of facilitators on the trainings provided.
- Measuring the performance of trainers/ facilitators by creating performance management system by tracking their KRA/KPIs along with providing them support to achieve the same, by providing mentoring and guiding sessions whenever required.
- Maintaining and tracking KRA/KPIs data, attendance of training data / reports, feedback data using MS Office and other tools for analyzing the effectiveness of training and for performing TNI (training need identification).
- Creating and maintaining performance measuring system to analyze the training needs of poor performers and appreciating the top performers.

- Documenting the growth journey of facilitators in monthly mails, training reports and center reviews timely with accuracy.
- Arranging and planning facilitators' recreational programs to provide them fun opportunities to showcase their hidden talent and provide a breather from routine tasks by taking new initiative every time.
- Taking initiatives for the teams, being the go-getter team member, enthusiastic to take new responsibilities, always in learning mode to provide best outcome for organization's goal

Tech Ascent as Trainer from

Jan 2017 to Jan 2018

- For various subjects such as Personality development, technical subjects like programming languages C++, C#, etc
- Helping trainees to provide learning opportunities by constantly motivating them
- Monitored, identified the training needs of trainees

Tulsiramji Gaikwad Patil College of Engineering As Asst. Professor

July 2013 to July 2014

- Trained students of MCA background for soft skill and IT subjects like .NET, C++, C#
- Arranged Seminars, presentations, engagement activities for students
- Being a Coordinator for event management of annual Technical and cultural Events "UDAAN-2013"
- Used variety of learning modalities and support materials to facilitate learning process and accentuate presentations.
- Assessment management for the students
- Took attendance, graded assignments and maintained student records to assist teachers with administrative tasks and maintain smooth daily operations

SKILLS

- Employee training and development
- Recruitment of trainers
- Content development and delivery
- Coaching and mentoring
- Analytical and Critical Thinking
- Online training experience
- Classroom expertise
- G-Suite, IT training
- MS Office
- Data organization and analysis
- Verbal and written communication
- Policies and process training Team management